Paranoia meets pandemonium.
1941 is a comedy, war film directed by Steven Spielberg.
In the days after the attack on Pearl Harbor, panic grips California,
where a military officer leads a mob chasing a Japanese sub.
Sgt. Frank Tree, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Ward Douglas, played by Ned Beatty.
Capt. Wild Bill Kelso, played by John Belushi.
Joan Douglas, played by Lorraine Gary.
Claude Crumn, played by Murray Hamilton.
Capt. Wolfgang von Kleinschmidt, played by Christopher Lee.
1941 is a 1979 American war comedy film directed by Steven
Spielberg and written by Robert Zemeckis and Bob Gale.
The film stars an ensemble cast including Dan Aykroyd, Ned Beatty, John Belushi, John Candy, Christopher Lee,
Tim Matheson, Toshiro Mifune, Robert Stack, Nancy Allen, and Mickey Rourke in his film debut.
The story involves a panic in the Los Angeles area after
the December 1941 attack on Pearl Harbor.
Co-writer Gale stated the plot is loosely based on what has come to be known as the Great Los Angeles Air Raid of 1942,
as well as the bombardment of the Ellwood oil refinery, near Santa Barbara, by a Japanese submarine.
Many other events in the film were based on real incidents, including
the Zoot Suit Riots and an incident in which the U.S.
Army placed an anti-aircraft gun in a homeowner's yard on the Maine coast.
1941 received mixed reviews and was not as financially successful as many of
Spielberg's other films, but was still a moderate box office success.
It received belated popularity after an expanded version aired on ABC in the 1980s, with
subsequent television broadcasts and home video reissues, raising it to cult status.
The film explores themes of california, panic,
submarine, war ship, world war ii.
The tone is lighthearted.